■
扫码加入我们
网络翻译爱好者联盟
本字幕由网络兴趣爱好者翻译完成
首发于字幕组网站  ZiMuZu.io
欢迎大家指正纠错  共同进步
■
翻译：爱可信的康纳  zouuoz  羽林加气  夏神
翻译：甜甜不姓布莱尼  夏棒棒
校对：爱可歆的康纳
时间轴：可爱的翻译们
后期：普罗米修斯
总监：普罗米修斯
CN
内容价值网络（Content Value Network）
非常感谢CVN项目方提供CVNT数字货币奖励支持CVN.io
本字幕仅供交流学习之用    所产生的任何纠纷请自行承担
欢迎更多网络翻译爱好者加入我们联盟一起学习交流进步
刚开始的时候很简单
It's simple at first.
家是你唯一知道的地方
Home is the only place you know.
那里的每一个人都是你的家人
And everyone there is your family.
我的第一个家充满了猫咪
My first home was full of cats.
而我是一只小狗
And I'm a dog.
猫有很尖的爪子
Cats had sharp claws
当它们开心的时候  还会发出奇怪的声音
and made a funny tummy sound when they were happy.
这些小猫咪有一个猫咪妈妈
The kittens had a mother cat.
我也有一个小狗妈妈
And I had a mother dog.
现在的生活已经完美无瑕
I couldn't imagine that life could get any better.
随着我的成长  我们一起组成了一个家
As I grew, we made a home together.
我们都很快乐
We were happy
但这仅仅只持续了一小段时间
for a while.
哇  看看  有这么多呢
Oh, wow. Look at all of 'em.
你可没告诉我  这有这么多
You didn't tell me there were so many.
快去抓住它们
Just grab 'em!
嘿  我找到一个  我这里抓到了一个
Hey! Found one. I got one over here.
天  它们跑的真快
Geez, they're fast.
我抓到一个
I got one.
这里  看这里  快来这边
Over there. Over there. Come here.
嘿  看  这里也有小狗
Hey, hey. There's dogs here, too.
哥哥
Brother!
这边还有好多
A whole bunch of 'em back here.
- 又抓到一个  - 姐姐
- Got another one. - Sister!
抓到了
Got it.
这有个成年期的斗牛犬
There's a full-grown pit bull.
来我这
Here we go.
放松
Easy.
成功了
Got her.
妈妈
Mother!
我要出去了  让开
I'm going out. Come on.
拿个大点的笼子
Get a bigger crate.
出来了
Coming out.
妈妈
Mother?
我再也没见过她
I never saw her again.
我不知道我会怎么样  如果没有猫咪妈妈的话
I don't know what would have happened to me without mother cat.
日子一天天过去了
And day by day,
渐渐的
little by little,
猫咪妈妈也成了我的妈妈
mother cat became my mother.
- 嘿  - 你好
- Hey. - Hey.
就在这
It's just here.
好吧  我们早下班只是为了能够
Okay. We left work early so we could be basically,
做这个吗  搞破坏  随便乱闯
what, breaking and entering?
这不是搞破坏或随便乱闯  奥莉薇亚
It's not breaking and entering, Olivia.
这是非法入侵  两者是有区别的
It's criminal trespass. There's a difference.
对对对  也就是做2年牢  而不是6年  知道了
Okay, so, like, two years in prison instead of six. Got it.
- 我还好  可不想坐牢  - 不管怎样  跟上来吧
- I'm good, I'm good.  - Anyway, come on.
你可不能说  救小猫的男人不够迷人
Can't say that a guy rescuing kittens isn't hot.
噢  我可没这么说  我只是说你不够迷人
Oh, I'm not saying that. I'm just saying you're not hot.
那多谢了  看这
Oh, thanks. Here.
- 快来  它们就在这下面  相信我  - 真的吗
- Come on. They're under here. Okay.  - Seriously?
卢卡斯  我可不要进这破洞
Lucas, I'm not going in that hole.
快来吧  你可是拯救动物志愿者
Well, you're the animal rescue volunteer.
- 好吧  - 你可以不用爬进去
- Okay.  - You don't have to crawl in.
就看一眼
Just take a look.
- 哇哦  有好多只  - 对吧
- Wow. There's so many of 'em.  - Yeah.
很明显  动物管理来过了
Apparently, animal control came,
但没把它们所有都带走
but they didn't get 'em all.
现在  建筑工说要把这一整片全拆了
And now, the builder says he's gonna tear down the whole block,
不管有没有猫在
cats or no cats.
之前那些人掳走了我的家人  但这个叫卢卡斯的人不一样
Men took my dog family, but this man named Lucas was different.
他每天都来
He came every day
猫咪们也都信任他
And the cats trusted him.
走吧
Come on.
在我开始思考之前  我的脚已经开始动了
And before I could even think, my paws were moving.
等等我
Wait!
卢卡斯  快看  一只小狗
Lucas! Look, a puppy!
天呐
Oh, my god.
嘿  你跑来这干什么  小狗狗
Hey. What are you doing here, baby... girl?
你好啊
Hey.
他舔起来也很舒服
And he tasted good, too.
她好可爱啊
She is really cute.
给你找个家应该不会很难
it will not be hard finding you a home.
额  等等
Well, wait.
要我说  你看见她是直接跑向我的
I mean, you saw how she ran right to me.
也许  她应该跟着我
Maybe that's a sign that her home's supposed to be with me.
卢卡斯  你不能照顾小狗狗的  你知道的
Lucas, you cannot take care of a dog, okay?
你上学的时候或者去当志愿者的时候  怎么办
What do you do when you go to school or the va?
听着  我和我妈妈住在一起
Listen, I actually live with my mom.
听起来有点怪  她是一名退伍军人
It's not how it sounds. It... she's a veteran.
你在退伍军人事务所也许见过她
You might have seen her at the va.
- 特里 雷 认识吗  - 知道
- Terri Ray?  - Yeah.
嗯  她现在还没找到个长久的工作
Well, she isn't able to hold down a job just yet,
所以  当我不在家的时候  她会在家
so, she's at home even when I'm not.
我想  养个小狗狗对她来说也会是件好事
Listen, maybe a puppy would be good for her, too.
没有任何事情能够像被他抱住一样感觉这么好
Nothing had ever felt as good as being held by him.
她确实看起来很喜欢你
She does really seem to like you a lot.
你看上他哪一点了  狗狗
What do you see in him that I don't, puppy?
听着  你们两个  滚开这里
Hey, you! Get out of there!
快走  快跑  别停下
Go, go, go. Go, go. Keep going.
这里可是私人财产
Private property!
- 一会儿见你  好吗  - 好的
- I'll see you later, okay?  - All right.
- 一会儿见  拜拜  - 记得给我打电话
- See you. Bye. - Call me.
- 你好  妈妈  - 你好
- Hi, mom.  - Hi.
我打算就叫她贝拉了
I think I'm gonna call her Bella.
宝贝  你知道我们不能养小狗的
Honey, you know we can't have a puppy.
租约上写着  不允许养宠物
Our lease says no pets.
人们说养狗对抑郁症有帮助
They say a dog is good for depression.
- 谁说的  - 我确定某个人说过的
- Who says that?  - Oh, I'm pretty sure somebody says that.
这就是那种我觉得是坏点子
Is this gonna be one of those things
但你仍然会去做的事情吗
I say is a terrible idea and you do it, anyway?
对啊  再说了 你觉得我从谁身上学的
Yeah. And who do you suppose I learned that from?
卢卡斯和我玩着最有意思的游戏
Lucas and I played the best games.
贝拉  抓住那个球
Bella, get the ball.
我们一起玩  抓球游戏
We played get the ball.
停下吧
Stop.
我们还一起玩  停下游戏
We played stop.
停下  贝拉  我还要学习呢
Stop, Bella. I have to study.
来这
Here.
给你玩我的毯子吧
Have my blanket.
毯子闻起来很好  味道就像卢卡斯
It smelled amazing. Just like Lucas.
我们还一起玩  不咬鞋子游戏
We played don't chew shoes.
贝拉  别咬鞋子
Bella. Don't chew shoes.
还有我最喜欢的游戏
And there was my favorite game of all.
怎么了  你想要什么
What? What do you want?
我还需要
I'm trying to...
你想要一小片芝士吗
Do you want a tiny piece of cheese?
小小的一片芝士
Tiny piece of cheese filled me
- 充满了大大的一片爱意  - 给你
- with such a strong feeling.  - There you go.
一瞬间  我感受到了  安全  开心  还有温暖
Like I was safe and happy and warm, all at once.
这就是  爱
It was love.
我要走了  来不及了  快走
I've got to go, got to go, got to go, got to go!
要迟到了
I'm so late.
要去工作了  再见  贝拉
Gotta go to work. Bye, Bella.
我最不喜欢的游戏就是  要去工作游戏
The one game I didn't like was go to work.
做个好孩子
Be good.
卢卡斯的毯子让我有了归属感
My Lucas blanket kept me company,
但这种归属感和真正的卢卡斯给的不一样
But it wasn't as same as the real Lucas
- 我还惦记着我的猫咪家庭  - 慢点
- I still had my cat family.  - Slow down there.
卢卡斯也变成了这个家庭的一份子
And Lucas became part of that family, too.
不  这个不是给你的 贝拉 这是留给猫咪们的  来这里
No, this is not for you, Bella. This is for the cats. Come here.
看见他们了吗
See 'em?
猫咪妈妈
Mother cat!
我喜欢猫咪妈妈  我也喜欢当贝拉
I love mother cat, and I love being Bella.
走吧  要回家了
Come on. We're going home.
希望一切都好  猫咪们
As you were, cats.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
好了  该睡觉了  贝拉  别闹了
All right. Bedtime, Bella. Come on.
每天结束的时候  我们会玩
And at the end of every day, we played...
坐  你准备好迎来
Sit. You ready for your
- 你的一小片芝士了吗  - 小片芝士游戏
- tiny piece of cheese?  - Tiny piece of cheese.
好了  去躺着毯子上吧  快去
All right. On your blanket. Come on.
晚安  贝拉
Night, Bella.
卢卡斯就是我的人  我就是他的狗狗
Lucas was my person, and I was his dog.
我有一个家了
I was home.
当卢卡斯要玩  去工作游戏  的时候
Whenever Lucas was playing go to work...
听话的狗狗
Good girl.
我会带着妈妈出去散步
I would take mom for a walk.
- 怎么了  小可爱  - 又是那个松鼠
- What is it, honey?  - It's that squirrel again!
我一定要抓住那个松鼠
I have to have that squirrel.
它就要跑掉了
It's getting away!
- 贝拉  听话  贝拉  - 它就在眼前了
- Bella. No, Bella. - Oh, it's right there!
走了  小家伙  别追逐松鼠了
Come on, girl. No squirrel chasing.
走了  贝拉  快跟我走  小家伙
Come on, Bella. Come on, girl.
我喜欢妈妈  但是她就是不知道
I loved mom, but she just didn't understand
- 怎么去追捕松鼠  - 听话点
- how to hunt squirrels. - Good.
挺好的小狗
Nice dog.
抱歉  不是故意吓到你的
Sorry. Didn't mean to startle you.
我叫冈特  贝肯鲍尔
I'm Gunter Beckenbauer.
那边就是我的房子
Those are my houses there.
你想要什么   贝肯鲍尔先生
What do you want, Mr. Beckenbauer?
叫我冈特就好
Oh, please, call me "Gunter."
我认的出这个味道
I knew that smell.
- 我知道这个味道不好  - 听我说
- And I knew this wasn't good.  - Look.
我知道你的儿子一直在给
I know it's your son who's been calling
城市建筑管理局打电话  说关于那些烦人的猫咪
the county building authority about the stupid cats,
我早摆脱那些猫了
which I got rid of.
我已经错过了整个暑期去施工了
I've lost the whole summer now,
所以  能不能让你儿子别来烦我了
so, could you please just ask him to back off?
我儿子不会让步的  贝肯鲍尔先生
My son isn't gonna back off, Mr. Beckenbauer,
因为还有猫住在那里的
because there are still cats living there.
动物管理局说那里没有
Animal control says there's not.
动物管理局在说谎  你也一样
Animal control is lying, and so are you.
那是条什么狗  斗牛犬吗
What kind of dog is that? Pit bull?
我们还不知道
We don't know.
我们发现它和那些  你说不存在的猫咪们  一起生活着
We found her living with the cats you say aren't there.
我想说的是  女士
What I'm trying to say, lady,
你和你的儿子不会想和我就此而开战的
is that you and your boy do not want to go to war with me.
你说开战  你知道什么是战争吗
War? What do you know about war?
好吧
Okay.
但是记住  我尝试过
But let the record show that I tried
想友好的解决这件事  但是你逼我的
to settle this friendly, and you're the one pushing it.
不  我记住的是  你来到这里  说要和我开战
No, the record shows that you came here and said we were going to war.
走了  贝拉  放松
Come on, Bella, relax.
放松  我们去把你的问题解决了
Relax. Let's go do your business.
这是什么东东  冰凉的  湿湿的
What is it? Cold, wet.
是冰淇淋
Ice cream!
冰淇淋从天上掉下来了
Ice cream is falling from the sky!
这是雪
It's snow.
只是下雪了而已  现在去上厕所吧
It's just snow. Now, do your business.
♪ 如果你想知道我笑起来是什么样
♪ If you wanna see what my smile looks like
此处BGM  “Together”
歌手  Andrew Allen
♪ 就来我身边吧
♪ come and be by my side
♪ 我们就整天都笑着
♪ we'll just laugh all day
♪ 如果你想知道星星是什么样
♪ if you wanna know what the stars are like
怎么了  怎么了
what? What?
♪ 今晚就和月亮一起逛逛吧
♪ Hang with the moon tonight
♪ 月亮离我们不算遥远
♪ it's not that far away
♪ 当我们在一起的时候
♪ when we're together whoa-oh
♪ 我们可以做任何事情
♪ we can do whatever whoa-oh
去吧  去吧
go on, go on.
加油  继续  上啊
Come on, go on. Go on.
♪ 在一起
♪ Together whoa-oh
♪ 天长地久
♪ Always forever whoa-oh
♪ 我们能找到在一起的意义
♪ we can find out what together's all about
去吧
go on. Yeah.
- 我爱死这雪了  - 再来
I loved snow do your business. Go on.
♪ 我们能找到在一起的意义
♪ We can find out what together's all about
- 耶  卢卡斯到家了  - 你好
- Yay! Lucas is home! - Hello.
卢卡斯一回家
When Lucas came home,
我就超级开心  你好  你好呀
I felt joy in my whole body. Hello. Hello.
- 这是什么  - 不知道
- What's that?  - I don't know.
它就贴在门上
It was taped to the door.
噢天
Oh, no.
是房东
It's the landlord.
他明天来检查水龙头
He's coming tomorrow to check the faucet.
但是我要去接受治疗  你也要去上班
But I have therapy and you have to work.
贝拉怎么办
What will we do with Bella?
房东来的时候  不能让她在家
She can't be in the house when he's here.
按计划行动
Just stick to the plan.
如果他们看到她了  你会被解雇的
If they see her, you're gonna get fired.
别担心
Don't worry.
确定没人  快来
All clear. Hurry up.
这一天  我可以玩  去工作游戏
That day, I got to do go to work.
贝拉  待在这儿
Bella. Okay, stay here. Stay.
我不喜欢待着
I didn't like stay.
不准叫  明白吗
No barks. Understand?
我一会儿再来看你
I'll come check on you in a little while.
贝拉  你不能被抓住的  好吗
You can't get caught, okay, Bella?
等等  你要去哪儿
Wait, hold on. Where are you going?
别叫哦
No barks.
我真是搞不懂这个游戏
I definitely do not get this game.
卢卡斯呢
Lucas?
疗程显示这对他没什么效果
PT reports he's not responding,
还是建议每天去两次
and recommends going to twice a day.
好的  我们可以试试  如果我们
Okay, well, we can try, but if he...
甘恩医生  抱歉失陪一下
Dr.Gann. Would you excuse me?
瓦莱丽  我去去就回
Hey, Valerie, I'll be right back. Yeah.
我的叫声起作用了
Yes, I was barking, but it worked.
- 你来啦  - 不
- Here you are.  - No.
把他叫过来  就是这个游戏吗
Is that the game?
是贝拉吗
Bella?
- 天呐  她都长这么大了  - 奥莉薇亚
- Oh, my gosh, she's gotten so big.  - Olivia
你知道有谁可以帮我照顾她吗
Hi. Do you know anybody here who could watch her,
我一个小时以后才有空
just for an hour or so, until my break?
只需要一个小时
Just an hour.
行吧  但是你从来没跟我提过
Okay, fine, but you know you only ever talk to me
你养动物出了点问题  对吗
when you have animal issues, right?
能打扰你们下吗
Am I interrupting something?
现在  这只狗不能违规待在这里
Now, this could not possibly be a dog in the va against all the regs.
我知道  特欧
I know, Teo.
但是今天没办法把贝拉单独留在家
We can't leave Bella home today.
如果房东发现我们养了条狗
If the landlord catches us with a dog,
我们会被赶出来的
we could get evicted.
好吧  我懂了
Now, I understand.
这个游戏就是大家挤在一个小房间里
The game is crowd in a small room.
贝拉  对吧
Bella, huh?
你知道吗
You know what?
我想到办法了
I've got this.
各位  都在吗
Everybody? Everybody?
今天的疗程  我带来了一位特别的嘉宾
Thought I'd bring a special guest to today's meeting.
希望你们见见这个可爱的狗狗贝拉
I'd like you to meet the lovely Bella.
- 嗨  贝拉  - 很好  非常好
- Hi, Bella.   - Great. That's great.
- 看看她  - 你戒酒多久了
- Look at that. - How long you been sober?
很久了吧
That long, huh?
老兄  这是个好主意
It was a good idea, man.
谢谢
Yeah. Thanks.
这偶尔会发生一次
It'll only happen once in a while. Yeah.
从那之后  我喜欢上了  去工作游戏
After that, I really liked go to work.
- 看起来她很喜欢呆在这儿  - 我也觉得
- Looks like she likes being here.  - I think she does, too.
我只是没动力
I just have no motivation.
就像  我知道这对我很好  但是
Like, I know it would be good for me, but...
我都快觉得妈妈的悲伤要烟消云散了
I could always feel mom's sadness going away
每当我安慰妈妈的时候
when I comforted her.
就像猫咪妈妈也会想起我一样
Like mother cat comforted me
迈克  你最近怎么样
Mack, what's it been like with you?
这  就像是
It's, uh... it's like...
就像是  一直都很痛苦
It's, like, pain all the time.
- 但妈妈不是唯一一个  - 每天早上
- But she wasn't the only one  - Every morning.
需要我安慰的人
Who needed me.
迈克是最难过的人
Mack was the most sad.
都是实话  发自肺腑的话
That's real. That's real talk.
- 你知道吗
- You know?
我想明天早上会再带她来
I'm gonna bring her again tomorrow.
看看谁来了
Look who's here!
现在  我有了很多新朋友
Now, I had lots of new friends.
- 快来  贝拉  - 看这个
- Come on, Bella.  - Look at that.
德鲁用他的小轮椅带我兜风
Drew took me on rides in his small car.
贝拉  张嘴
Bella, open.
史蒂夫用勺子喂我的东西超美味
Steve had really delicious spoons.
我的一些朋友们还有狗牌  和我一样
Some of my friends had tags, just like me.
好孩子
Aw, good girl.
贝拉
Bella
贝拉  趴着
Bella, get down.
我们去洗衣服  趴着
We're doing laundry. Down.
我很喜欢玩  洗衣服游戏
I really liked doing laundry.
而且大家都在玩一个叫甘恩医生的游戏
And everyone played a game called Dr. Gann.
医生  来了
Doctor! Hal.
甘恩医生来了  我们走
Dr. Gann. Hey, let's go.
甘恩医生  早上好  你怎么样了
Hey, Dr. Gann. Good morning. How are you?
甘恩医生  你进去  进去
Dr. Gann. In you go. In you go!
你要进去吗  还是
Were you going in, or...
- 感谢  谢谢你  - 你转身
- Appreciate it. Thank you. - Your turn.
- 噢 撞上了  - 好的  别这样
Oh, shoot. Okay, no...
- 慢慢来  - 好的  谢谢
Take your time. Okay. Thank you.
没关系  早上好
All right. Good morning.
- 早上好  医生  - 大家早上好
- Good morning, doc.  - Good morning, everyone.
早上好  甘恩医生
Good morning, Dr. Gann
- 早  - 医生 怎么了
- Morning. - What's up, doc?
还好
Okay.
有什么问题吗
Everything all right?
拜拜  医生
Bye, doc.
好孩子  多听话的孩子
Good girl. What a good girl.
让我们再来玩一次吧
Let's do that again!
- 太聪明了  - 好孩子
- So smart.  - Good girl.
我觉得昨晚上很有意思
I had fun last night.
对啊
Me, too.
现在  卢卡斯和我随时都在找那只松鼠
Now, whenever Lucas and I went looking for that squirrel,
- 奥莉薇亚也一起来了  - 下次  行吗
- Olivia came, too.  - Next time, all right?
所以  还有下次吗  知道了
So, there's gonna be a next time? Got it.
对的  就这样
All right, let's go.
- 帮忙牵着贝拉  - 好
Take Bella? Yeah.
- 我打电话叫人  - 好
- I'm gonna call the rescue.- Yeah.
嘿
Hey!
等下  停下
Wait! Stop!
你们在干什么
What the hell you doing?
这还住着很多猫  你们不能这样做
There are still cats living there. You can't do this.
- 我们有许可证  - 这不重要
- We've got a permit.  - That doesn't matter.
- 你逗我吗  - 嘿
-You kidding me?  - Hey!
- 我受够你了  你疯了吧  - 他们在路上了
- I have had enough of you, you crazy...  - They're on it.
过来我们谈谈
Can I talk to you for a minute?
你为什么要来搅和我的事
Why you screwing with my life?
你怎么拿到的许可证
How did you even get a permit?
私人财产认证  不包括猫
Property's certified. No cats.
- 喂  - 我在直播  摧猫辣手
Hey. - I'm live-streaming, cat killer.
这里没猫
There are no cats!
猫咪妈妈
Mother cat!
你们去哪儿
Where are you going?
没猫吗
No cats?
我工作的救援组织刚刚打电话给
The rescue organization that I work with just called the building
建筑委员会  要求吊销你的许可证
commission to have your permit yanked.
真希望他们能在拆完之前赶来
Like they move that fast.
我们一个董事会成员打过电话了  他们马上就来
They do when our board member calls.
她是城市委委员
She's a county commissioner.
冈特
Hey, Gunter.
啥事
yeah.
是关于你许可证的事情
It's about your permit.
那到底是谁在敲门
Who on earth could that be?
不知道  我去开门
I don't know. I'll get it.
抱歉打扰
Excuse me.
有人投诉你
There's been a complaint that
藏匿了一只危险动物
you may be harboring a dangerous animal.
投诉吗  是谁
A complaint? From who?
我想你知道  在丹佛养斗牛犬是违法的
As you may know, pit bulls are illegal in the city of Denver.
只要它在你家里面  我们是不会动它的
As long as it's on your property, we can't touch it.
- 我记得他  - 我现在告诉你
- I remember him.  - I am informing you
但如果你的狗在大街上被逮住
that if that dog gets picked up on the street,
它会被收押
it will be impounded.
晚安
Have a nice night.
好吧  贝拉  这很重要
Okay, Bella, this is very important.
我们要再试一次
We're gonna try this again.
行  准备好了吗
Okay. You ready?
现在  跑回家
And...go home
贝拉  就是这样  跑回去
That's it, Bella. Go home.
最棒的游戏
Best game ever!
回家游戏就是说  我要把我的头放在这里
Doing go home meant I should put my head right here.
太棒了  你成功了
Yes! You did it!
你回家了  非常棒
You did go home. Well done.
- 真难忘  -  贝拉  做得好
- That was impressive.- Good job, Bella.
好姑娘
Good girl. Wow.
所以  现在  一旦我们带离开贝拉了房子
So, now, if we take Bella off the property
管理动物的人想带走它  我们只需要说  回家
and animal control tries to take her, we just say, "go home."
我喜欢让卢卡斯高兴
I loved making Lucas happy.
是那只松鼠
That squirrel!
我必须捉住那只松鼠
I had to have that squirrel.
松鼠  松鼠  站住
Squirrel, squirrel, squirrel!
贝拉呢
Bella?
贝拉
Bella!
贝拉  我一直在到处找你
Bella, I've been looking all over for you.
坏狗狗
Bad dog.
贝拉  你不可以  再这样了
Bella, you can never, ever do that again.
我不在乎窗户怎么样了  但是你不能再乱跑了
I don't care about the window, but you cannot run away.
在那儿牵住它  伙计
Hold it right there, pal.
我要收押这只狗
I'm impounding that animal.
- 不  你不可以  - 我可以这么做  那是我帮手
No, you are not. Yes, I am, and that's my backup.
这是斗牛犬  而且这是法定扣押
This is a pit bull. And this is a legal impoundment.
如果它要跑  你逮着它
If he resists, you arrest him.
回家  贝拉
Go home, Bella.
贝拉  回家
Bella, go home.
- 贝拉  回家  - 但你需要我
- Go home, Bella.  - But you need me.
贝拉
Bella
贝拉  快  回家
Bella, please, go home.
贝拉  求你了  回家  贝拉
Bella, please. Go home, Bella.
没事
That's right.
- 这样很容易  - 贝拉  回家
- Easy does it. - Bella, go home.
放松  抓到了
Easy. There we go.
别这样做
Don't do that.
- 先生  - 够了
-  sir. - come on.
先生  松手  马上
Sir, let go, now.
你需要松手让他带走这只狗
You need to let him have the dog.
不能让她这样被绑着
Not with that on her.
放开
Let go.
查克  让他来
Chuck, let him do it.
没事的  贝拉
It's okay, Bella.
没事的 没事的 我陪着你呢
It's okay. It's okay. I got you.
跟着我
Follow me.
没事的  我抱着你  宝贝  没事的
It's okay. I got you, baby. It's okay.
没事的
It's okay.
贝拉  我搞砸了
Bella, I screwed up.
真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
- 好了好了  - 突然之间
- All right.  - All of a sudden,
- 我闻到很多其他狗的气味  - 好了好了  没事了
- I smelled so many other dogs. - You're okay. It's all right.
我会来接你的  贝拉  明白吗
I will come get you, Bella. Understand?
很抱歉我没有回家  卢卡斯
I'm sorry I didn't do go home, Lucas.
- 我不会让他们伤害你的  - 好了  可以了
- I will not let them hurt you. - Okay, that's enough.
请离开车辆
Step away, please.
请你走开
Step away.
别走
Please.
卢卡斯
Lucas?
这里面好吵  所有狗都好伤心
It was so loud, and all the dogs were so sad.
到了
Okay.
进去吧
In you go.
我想  如果我做一只很乖的狗  他们会让我回到卢卡斯身边
I thought if I did good dog, they'd let me go back to Lucas.
我坐下了
I did sit.
我坐了很久
I did sit some more.
我没有叫
I did no barks.
我叫了很多次
I did lots of barks.
我真的需要卢卡斯的毯子
I really needed my Lucas blanket.
我那个时候应该跑回家的
I should have done go home.
出来吧
Come on.
你好啊
Hello.
等等
Hang on.
我看你不像是
Aw, you don't seem like
一只危险的动物呀  可爱的姑娘
such a dangerous animal to me, sweet girl, hmm?
来吧  来吧
Come on. Come on.
- 嘿  - 卢卡斯
- Hey! - Lucas
- 嘿  嘿  - 我准备好玩跑回家游戏了
- Hi. Hi. - I'm ready to do go home.
嘿  看  我来啦
Hey. See, I'm here.
- 我来啦  - 不用问了
- I'm here. - Well, there's question one.
这显然是你的狗
She's obviously your dog.
好孩子  我知道  我知道  好孩子
Good girl. I know. I know. Good girl.
好啦  可以啦
All right. There you go.
你已经交了罚款
So, you've paid the fine.
我只需要给你释放材料就好了
I just need to give you the discharge information.
在丹佛  一条狗被定义为斗牛犬的条件是
In Denver, all that's required for a dog to be classified as a pit bull
让三名动物管理局的人员认证她
is for three animal control officers to certify that it is.
贝拉已经被认证为斗牛犬了
And Bella has been certified pit bull.
被认证为斗牛犬意味着什么呢
What does "certified pit" mean?
这意味着如果她再被抓到  她就会被安乐死
It means if they pick her up again, she'll be euthanized.
- 什么  - 这就是法律
-What?  - That's the law.
斗牛犬是一个很宽泛的描述  就像猎犬一样
Pit bull's a pretty loose description. It's like saying "hound dog."
因此  市议会最终投票决定
So, the city council essentially voted that
可以因为一条狗的长相而将其在全市禁止
a dog can be banned from the city because of how it looks.
这算是狗类的种族歧视
That's basically racism for dogs.
是的  这太蠢了
I know. It's stupid.
贝拉是世界上最温顺的狗
I mean, Bella is the most gentle dog in the world.
你应该看看她在医院与退伍军人的相处
You should see her at the hospital with the veterans.
他们很喜欢她
I mean, they love her.
如果我们搬家怎么样
What about if we move?
比如说搬到戈尔登或者城市以外的地方
Like, Golden or somewhere out of the city limits?
这样是可以的
That works.
或者  可有找其他人照顾她吗
Meanwhile, do you have someone who can look after her?
我叔叔一家人住在法明顿
My aunt and uncle, they live in Farmington.
- 或许他们能帮助我们  - 法明顿在新墨西哥州吧
- Maybe they could help us. - New Mexico?
好像有400英里远吧
It's like 400 miles.
我真的准备好回家了
I'm really ready to do go home now.
好啦  开始收拾吧  找到你的恐龙了
All right, here we go. Got your dinosaur.
还有什么呢
What else do we have?
你能这么做真的太好了
It's so good of you to do this.
我们很乐意帮忙
We're just happy to help.
奥莉薇亚真是个甜心
Olivia's such a sweetheart.
好吧  差不多了
Well, this is it.
我先去车里
I'll be in the car.
为什么每个人都这么悲伤呢
Why is everyone so sad?
我们都已经在家了
We're all home, now.
贝拉  真的很抱歉
Bella, I'm so sorry.
再见了
See you soon.
好了  我从后窗偷偷出去
Okay, I'll sneak out the back window.
至少没有帘子在挡着了
At least there's no screen on that one.
不要怕  我来给你系上
Here, I got ya, I got ya.
你好啊
Hello.
住手
Stop.
你的帮手不可能这么快就来帮你吧
Backup can't possibly get here fast enough to help you.
我们明白你在这里玩的小把戏
We understand the little game that you're playing here.
是冈特  对吧
It's Gunter, isn't it?
你在帮他做事吗
You work for him?
也许你们只是朋友
Maybe you're just buddies.
现在  你要让我儿子
Now, you're gonna let my son
走到那辆车前和他的狗狗说再见
walk to that car to say goodbye to his dog
但是你不能进行干涉
without any interference from you.
明白吗
Copy?
明白
Copy.
上车吧  贝拉  就是这样
Go on, Bella. That's it.
你真是个乖狗狗  贝拉
You're such a good girl, Bella.
我知道你理解不了  但是我不是在抛弃你
I know you won't understand, but I'm not abandoning you.
我只是不得不把你送到安全的地方
I just have to send you somewhere safe.
我们要去哪里
Where are we going?
为什么我不能和你一起坐在前面
Why can't I ride in the front with you?
给你
Here.
你得带着你的毯子
You got to have your blanket.
他为什么给了我卢卡斯的毯子
Why did he bring my Lucas blanket?
毯子应该在床上才对
It should be on my bed.
我保证  用不了太久  你就可以回家了
I promise, very soon, you'll get to go home.
卢卡斯说  回家吧  但是他关上门
Lucas said, "go home," but then he shut the door.
我需要卢卡斯
I need Lucas!
求你了 别走
Please! No!
他的气味正在消失
His scent was fading.
我离他越来越远了
I was getting farther and farther away.
我闻着卢卡斯毯子的味道  不是那么难过了
I smelled my Lucas blanket to feel better,
但是它不是卢卡斯
but it wasn't Lucas.
坐下
Sit.
贝拉  来这边
Bella, come here.
对
Yes.
你真乖  很好  真乖
Oh, you're so pretty. Yes, you are.
这些人很好
These people were nice.
他们照顾我  但他们不是我的家人
They took care of me, but they weren't my family.
这里不是我的家
This wasn't home.
喂
Hello?
一切都好吗
How is everything?
放心  她很好
Oh, she's fine. Yeah.
真的吗  可以啊
Really? Okay.
那好  明天见
All right. See you tomorrow, then.
你猜怎么着
Guess what?
他们在戈尔登找到了一个好地方
They found a nice place in Golden,
他们明天来接你
and they're coming to get you tomorrow.
我打赌你已经准备好回家了  贝拉  你是条好狗
I bet you're ready to go home. You're a good dog, Bella.
乔斯说  回家吧
José said, "go home."
- 你是一只好狗  - 但是怎么回去呢
- You're a good dog. - But how?
晚安
Good night.
那种感觉又来了
That feeling came again.
我本来应该和卢卡斯在一起的
I was supposed to be with Lucas.
我得想办法找到他
I had to find a way to get to him.
我不知道那很吵的东西是什么
I didn't know what that loud thing was,
但乔斯确实喜欢带着它在院子里散步
but José sure liked to take it for walks around the yard.
但我记得之前下雪的时候我见过这个
But I do remember that from snow do your business.
等等
Wait.
有了
Yes!
我下定决心了
I'm doing it!
我要玩回家游戏
I'm doing go home!
看起来回家的路真的很远
I could tell that go home was very far away.
但我知道我走的方向是对的
But I knew that I was going in the right direction.
现在的感觉像是一根无形的绳子  我被牵着
The feeling now was a pull, like I was on a leash
然后告诉我回家的路
and being told how to do go home.
如果我一直走下去  我坚信我会再见到卢卡斯
And if I kept going, I knew I would see Lucas again.
到了第一天晚上  我已经很累了
By that first night, I was so tired.
而且周围有很多奇怪的气味
And there were so many strange smells.
那是什么
What's that?
它长得像猫  但闻起来像一条狗
It looks like a cat, but it smells like a dog.
希望它不会回来了
I hope it doesn't come back.
早餐时间到了
It was breakfast time,
但是我到处都找不到吃的东西
but I couldn't find a bowl of food anywhere.
它没放在碗里
It's not in a bowl,
但我就吃它了
but I'll take it.
这顿早餐跑的真快呀
This breakfast is really fast!
我想吃早餐
I need breakfast!
这顿早餐比那只松鼠还难抓
This breakfast was harder to hunt than that squirrel.
我从来都没有这么饿过
I was hungrier than I'd ever been.
有人
People.
下面有人
There are people down there.
杜兰戈  科罗拉多州
一群狗狗
A pack.
或许我不该打扰他们
Maybe I shouldn't bother them.
但我太饿了
But I'm so hungry.
独牙仔的牙好大呀
One Tooth is big.
出于礼貌  我还是仔细嗅一下  看看他们有没有留下记号  占了这地方
To be polite, I'll carefully sniff where the other dogs have marked.
什么
What?
管事的竟然是疯发犬
Oh, crazy hair is in charge.
谢谢
Thanks.
这是一个很棒的狗群
This was a great pack.
他们知道去哪儿能吃到最好的鸡肉
They knew just where to go fo get the best chicken.
嘿  你们来了
Hey. There you are.
今天的特色菜  鸡肉
Yeah, today's special. Chicken.
你的最爱  是吧
You like that. You like...
我喜欢这个鸡肉男
I love this chicken guy.
好了  很好  就这些啦  没有啦
Okay, very good. That's it. That's it.
你们现在可以走啦  好吗  去吧
You can go now, okay? Go.
来了
Coming.
独牙仔是一个勇敢的猎食者
One Tooth was a brave hunter,
他无所畏惧
who wasn't afraid of anything.
向他学习猎食太令我兴奋了
It was exciting to learn to hunt from him.
这个狗群太好玩了
This pack was so much fun.
你们好呀  小宝贝们
Hello. sweethearts.
你是谁呀  新来的吗
Oh, and who are you? Are you new?
给你  小家伙  好的
There you go, sweethearts. Yeah.
该回家了  回家吧  快回家吧
Please go home, now. Go on home, now. Go on home.
她怎么知道我正在玩回家游戏
How did she know I was doing go home?
回家吧
Go home!
- 真是个美妙的一天  - 好孩子
- It was a wonderful day. - Good boy, sarge.
但是独牙仔这是去哪儿呢
But where's one tooth going?
好了  进来吧  快点
All right, in you go. Come on.
丑屁股也要走了吗
And shaggy butt, too?
看来只剩下你和我了 疯发犬
Guess that just leaves you and me, crazy hair.
等等
Oh, Wait.
狗群里的每个成员都有自己的家人
Everyone in this pack has their own people.
疯发犬想让我跟他进去
Crazy hair wanted me to go with him,
成为他家庭中的一员
to be part of his family.
里面看起来很不错  闻上去也很好
It seemed nice in there, with lots of good smells.
在这里我也可能会很开心
I could be happy here.
但他们并不需要我
But they didn't need me.
妈妈需要我
Mom needed me.
卢卡斯需要我
Lucas heeded me.
我也需要他们
And I needed them.
露西  你回来啦
Lucy! There you are.
所以  我要继续我的回家游戏
So, I had to keep doing go home.
现在我知道了  想要猎食的话
Now, I knew that to hunt,
我需要去有人的地方
I needed to go where there were people
然后按照独牙仔教我的来
and do what one tooth taught me.
有血的味道
I smelled blood.
它是我见过最大的动物
It was the largest animal I had ever seen.
她遇到了很恐怖的事情
And something very bad had happened to her.
快来  在这里
Come on! Whoo! Through here.
我看到它了
I see it.
它肯定值千把块
Thing's got to be worth a thousand bucks.
至少呀 太棒了
Oh, at least. Beautiful.
你觉得它有一百多斤吗
What do you figure? About 125 pounds?
太给力了
Oh, yeah.
- 来张自拍吧  - 好啊
- Hey, let's get a selfie.  - Yeah, you bet.
准备好了吗
Okay, ready?
- 好了  - 看镜头
- Yeah.  - Here.
她可真美
Wow. She's beautiful.
不错吧  这照片一定要挂墙上
Yeah, that one's going up on the wall.
那是什么
What is that?
看起来有点像猫
It kind of looks like a cat.
我希望它跟我走
I hoped the cat would leave with me
别被坏人抓住
and not get caught by those bad men.
她和我见过的猫闻起来不一样
That cat didn't smell like any cat I ever knew.
它在跟着我吗
Was it following me?
还好  跟着呢
Yep, it was following me.
我突然意识到它不是一只成年的猫
And suddenly, I realized it wasn't a full-grown cat.
还是一个猫宝宝
It was still just a kitten.
就是长的太大了
A really big kitten.
大猫咪  快来这边
Come on, big kitten. This way.
那只大动物肯定是它妈妈
That big animal must have been this kitten's mother.
大猫咪让我想起了我的狗狗妈妈
Big kitten made me think of mother dog
以及  她被抓走时  我有多难过
and how sad I was when she was taken away.
她需要人照顾她
She needed someone to take care of her.
大猫咪的妈妈再也不能喂养她了
Big kitten's mother couldn't feed her anymore,
那么  就由我来照顾她吧
so, I did.
我成了大猫咪的猫妈妈了
I was big kitten's mother cat now.
大猫咪需要进食  我也要吃饭
Big kitten needed to eat, and so did I.
所以我做了所有妈妈都会做的事
So, I did what any mother would do.
去觅食
I went hunting.
♪ 你在拐角处叫住了我
♪ Stop me on the corner
此处BGM “Brighter Than the Sun”
歌手  Colbie Caillat
小宝宝  对不起啦
Sorry, baby!
♪ 就像意想不到的梦境让我着迷
♪ I swear you hit me like a vision I wasn't expecting
♪ 但我有资格让命运按照我的意愿出现吗
♪ but who am I to tell fate where it's supposed to go with it?
♪ 别眨眼  机会可能就这么消失了
♪ Don't you blink, you might miss it
♪ 我们可以选择珍惜它或不管它
♪ see, we got a right to just love it or leave it
♪ 也可以找到它并留下它
♪ you find it and keep it
♪ 不是每天都有机会这样说的
♪ 'cause it ain't every day you get the chance to say
嘿  嘿  放下它
hey! Hey! Drop it!
♪ 就像闪电击中心脏  如枪炮般强烈
♪ Lightning strikes the heart. It goes off like a gun
♪ 可与日光媲美
♪ brighter than the sun
♪ 就像繁星
♪ oh, we could be the stars
♪ 从天而降
♪ falling from the sky
♪ 发出光芒
♪ shining how we want
♪ 比阳光还灿烂
♪ brighter than the sun
很多时候  大猫咪都会在夜晚出去
Many nights, big kitten would wander off on her own.
而我就去睡觉  梦到家人
I would sleep and dream of home.
你准备好来小小一片的奶酪了吗
You ready for your tiny piece of cheese?
给你  乖狗狗
Here you go. Good girl.
你真是个乖狗狗  贝拉
You're such a good dog, Bella.
时光流转  大猫咪变得更大了
As time passed and big kitten got bigger,
她似乎仍不理解我为什么要回家
she still didn't seem to understand how to go home.
所以  当她想把我带偏路线时
So, when she tried to take me away from it,
我总得把她带回来
I would always have to bring her back.
不管大猫多晚出去  都有人给她吃的
Whenever big kitten went out at night, someone gave her food.
猫都爱吃鱼
Cats love fish,
但我希望有人能给她鸡肉就好了
but I wish someone would give her chicken.
夜里我们互相取暖
We kept each other warm.
我们已经是彼此的家人了
We were family now.
一个早上  我闻到了些特别的气味
I had been smelling something all morning.
有点像狗
Something like dog.
之后  我先听到了它的声音
First, I heard them.
接着就看到它了
Then I saw them.
他们的眼神冷酷
Their eyes were cold.
他们是来找我们猎食的
They were hunting us.
我必须得保护好大猫咪
And I had to protect big kitten.
嘿  快走  离开这里
Hey! Get out! Get out of here!
滚开  快滚开
Scram! Get out!
哎 你看
Hey, check it out.
- 那是山猫吗  - 不  是一只美洲狮
- Is that a bobcat?  - No, no, it's a cougar.
这只还很小
It's a young cougar.
大猫害怕这些人
Big kitten was afraid of the men.
哇  速度真快
Whoa. That's really fast.
但我决定看看他们会不会给我们吃的
But I decided to see if they would give us food.
今天吓到我了
Pretty scared to me.
我从没在野外见过美洲狮
I've never seen a cougar in the wild before.
这家伙超大  得有3米吧
I mean, this thing was huge. It was like 10 feet long.
别紧张  也就3.6米
Easy, 12. Yeah.
来  让我看看你狗牌上的名字
Hey. Let's see if your name is on your tag, huh?
狗狗很乖啊
Who's a good girl?
这只小狗挺可爱的
She's a cutie. She is.
想吃火腿吗
Want some ham?
来  给你火腿  坐  乖狗狗
There's your ham. There you go. Sit. Oh, good girl.
她叫贝拉
Her name is Bella.
好姑娘  伸只爪子来  真配合
Give me a paw. Good girl. There you go.
牌子上有电话号码  写着  卢卡斯 雷
And there's a telephone number. "Lucas ray."
卢卡斯吗
Lucas?
我来联系他
I'm gonna call the guy.
兄弟们  这边好像有东西在动
Hey, guys, I think there's something moving out there.
转到语音信箱了
Okay, it's going to voice mail.
你好  你呼叫了卢卡斯 雷
Hi. You've reached Lucas Ray...
就是他啊
That's him!
麦克拉伦退伍军人医院的档案助理
Assistant case manager at McLaren va hospital.
有事请留言
Please leave a message.
如果你关于我家走丢的狗  贝拉  的信息
If you're calling about my lost dog Bella...
天啊  她有点受惊了
Man, she's kind of freaking out.
拜托了  请留下你的号码
Please, leave your number
或者打给奥莉薇亚
or call Olivia at 612-589-1743.
我去  什么鬼
What?
是美洲狮  天呐  快上车
Cougar! Get in the truck! Oh, god.
我在这儿呢  卢卡斯
I'm here, Lucas.
是我啊  我在这里啊
I'm here. I'm here.
下雪了  是上厕所时间了
It's snow do your business!
♪ 雷声滚滚  隆隆声
♪ Hear the thunder it's rolling, it's rolling
此处BGM  “Jump Right In”
歌手  Laney Jones
♪ 远远地传来
♪ it calls from far away
♪ 你的心脏在跳动
♪ hear your heart it's beating,
♪ 伴着轻快的节奏
♪ it's beating the easy rhythm it plays
♪ 踏上前方征程
♪ pressing on to the journey ahead
♪ 从头开始
♪ we do it all over again
♪ 如果你犹豫了
♪ And if you're holding back
♪ 不要多想  即刻启程
♪ jump right in
♪ 不坠落  如何飞翔
♪ you can't fly without falling
♪ 不摔倒  怎么会奔跑
♪ you can't run without crawling
♪ 不发声  又如何高歌
♪ You can't sing without making a sound
♪ 来  深吸一口气  再呼出来
♪ so breathe in and let it out
♪ 即刻启程吧
♪ jump right in
♪ 不坠落  如何飞翔
♪ you can't fly without falling
♪ 不摔倒  怎么会奔跑
♪ you can't run without crawling
♪ 不发声  又如何高歌
♪ you can't sing without making a sound
♪ 深吸一口气  再呼出来
so breathe in and let it out
♪ 即刻启程吧
♪ jump right in
她很轻松就过去了呢
She acted like that was easy.
有一只狗哎
A dog!
我很久没和狗玩过了
It's been so long since I played with a dog.
达驰  你叫什么啊
Dutch, what are you barking at?
拜托你  安静点  快闭嘴
Be quiet. Come on!  Shut up!
达驰
Dutch!
这只蠢狗
You stupid mutt!
达驰
Dutch!
快离开那里啊
Get out of there!
达驰
Dutch!
我能闻到另一只狗身上的恐惧
I can smell the fear of the other dog.
他一定在下面  这些是他养的狗
He must be down here. These are his dogs.
- 就在这儿  - 加把劲
- Here! Here!   - Come on.
还有呼吸吗
Is he breathing?
快去报警
Call 911.
来  头朝上
Okay, head up.
- 他会没事吗  - 会的
- Is he gonna make it?  - Yeah.
你们救了他
You saved his life.
这些狗怎么办  都是他的
What about the dogs? These are his.
我觉得  这应该你们自己决定
I mean, I guess that's up to you guys.
我可以替你们联系动物管理局
We can call animal control for you,
可我们不能在这儿等
but we can't wait for them.
抱歉  伙计们  祝你们好运吧
Sorry, guys. Good luck.
看来我们得带它们走了
I guess they go with us.
来吧  狗狗们
Come on, dogs.
大猫咪啊
Big kitten!
来吧  走了
Come on. Come on.
别把我从她身边带走  她需要我
Don't take me away from her. She needs me.
来吧  狗狗们  走了
Come on, dogs. Come on.
不  我不能走
No.
快走了  来吧
Come on. Come on.
求你们了
Please.
达驰  到这边来
Dutch, come here.
进来吧  乖狗狗  你可以信任我们
Come on, girl. You can trust us.
为什么我觉得你其实很乐意带这些狗呢
Why do I get the feeling you're secretly enjoying this?
我喜欢狗
I like dogs.
不过  我们得给她多喂些吃的
We need to feed this girl more, though.
都能看到她的肋骨了
You can see her ribs.
我要出去啊
Out.
嘿  不  不  不要抓玻璃
Hey, no, no, no, no. No. Don't scratch.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
莫莉吗  还是艾莉
Molly? Ellie?
放我出去啊
Let me out.
- 布兰奇吗 - 叫他布兰奇吗
- Blanche.  - Blanche?
你在搞笑吧
You got to be kidding me.
我妈的狗就叫布兰奇
My mother's dog was named Blanche.
好吧  原来如此
Well, that explains a lot.
看到了吗  他喜欢这里
See? He likes it here.
加文  我们得把狗还给他
Gavin, we have to give the guy his dogs back.
我要看黄金女郎
I like the Golden Girls.
大猫咪的气味很淡  但我还是能闻到
Ever so faintly, I could smell big kitten on the wind.
她在等我
She was waiting for me.
除了她  还有卢卡斯  还有我的家
And beyond her, Lucas and go home.
你叫比亚特丽丝吗  米莉吗  还是索菲
Beatrice? Millie? Sophie?
赛迪吗
Sadie?
克洛伊呢
Chloe?
贝拉吗
Bella
是贝拉吗
Bella?
真是贝拉  我就知道
Bella! See? See, I told you.
你叫贝拉啊  乖狗狗
It's Bella. That's a good dog.
他怎么知道我的名字的
How did he know my name?
你的名字是贝拉
Your name is Bella.
当我们回去时
When we get back to the city, yeah,
我会给你个有你名字的狗牌
I'm gonna get you a tag with your name on it.
对啊  我就要这么做
I am. Yes, I am.
加文  你真够了
Gavin.
达奇喜欢这里  我也喜欢
Dutch liked it here, and so did I.
想吃的时候就有东西吃
We had food whenever we needed it.
要来点零食吗
Want a snack?
房间里很暖和
We were inside and warm.
睡觉的地方也很软和
Dutch and I had a soft spot to sleep on.
我们还有彼此相伴
And each other.
有点像家一样了
It started fo feel like home.
这是什么
What's this?
为了庆祝你写完了小说
To celebrate you finishing your novel.
过来
Hey. Come here.
你把我们的电话号码写在狗牌上了吗
Did you put our phone number on their dog tags?
不然我要加上谁的号码
Well, whose number would I put on it?
这种味道很熟悉
This smell was familiar.
你要帮我吗
You helping me?
你喜欢叠衣服吗  贝拉
You like doing laundry, Bella?
- 喂  - 洗衣服游戏  我玩过这个游戏
- Hello. - Doing laundry? I knew that game.
我猜你是喜欢的
Guess you do, huh?
好啦
Yeah.
谁的电话
What is it?
稍等我一会儿
Uh, can you excuse me, please?
是雪崩时候的那个人他妹妹
That guy from the avalanche... His sister.
他出院了
He's out of the hospital.
对不起  我
I'm sorry, I...
嗯 他没事就好
Yes, I'm sure he is.
达驰以前一定来过这里
Dutch had definitely been here before.
他把院子里所有东西都做了记号
He had marked just about everything in the yard.
听话  达驰  听话
Easy, Dutch. Easy.
在吗  库尔奇先生
Hello? Mr. Kurch?
过来  贝拉  库尔奇先生  在吗
Come on, Bella. Mr. Kurch? Hello?
我在后屋
Back here.
哦  达驰
Aw! Geez! Oh, Dutch.
下去
Get down!
达驰就是见到你太激动了
Well, Dutch is just happy to see you.
我身上11处骨折  这条狗直接跳到我身上了
I got 11 freaking fractures, and the dog's jumping all over me.
从我身上下去  蠢狗
Get off of me, stupid dog!
达驰见到这个人很兴奋
Dutch was happy to see this man,
但是竟然有人见到达驰会不开心
but what kind of a man wouldn't be happy to see Dutch?
我是泰勒  这是加文
I'm Taylor. This is Gavin.
是我们把你挖出来的
We're the ones who dug you out.
我一点都不记得了
I don't remember any of that.
我只知道我妹妹说  你们要把狗带过来
All I know is my sister says you're bringing the dog over,
真是可笑
which is ridiculous.
可笑吗
Ridiculous?
我不太明白
I don't understand you.
我看起来像是能照顾一条狗的人吗
Do I look like I can take care of a dog?
但是这是你的两条狗啊
But they're your dogs.
谁说两条狗了  我从来没见过另一条狗
Dogs? I never even seen that other one before.
贝拉不是你的狗吗
Bella's not yours?
但是她很努力的把你挖出来呀
But she was trying to dig you out.
我那条狗都不会养
I'm not taking either one.
但你至少要养达驰
But you have to take Dutch at least.
你们要怎么处理那条狗
Whatever you're doing with that other one,
就怎么处理达驰
do the same thing with Dutch.
走吧  狗狗们
Come on, dogs.
我们走  达驰  过来
Let's go, Dutch. Come on.
过来
Come on.
- 走吧  - 那个人活该孤单
- Come on.  - That man belongs alone.
过来
Come here.
过来  贝拉
Come here, Bella.
乖狗狗
Good girl. Hey.
所以我们有了两条傻乎乎的大狗
So, now, we have two big, slobbery dogs.
就像我一直以来的期盼一样
Just like I've always wanted.
他们很乖的
Oh, they're good dogs.
是的  过来
Yeah, they are. Hey, come here.
过来  贝拉  过来  抓到你了
Come here, Bella. Come here. There you are.
等下  等下  等下
Hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
雪化了  但是我知道我在哪
The snow was gone, but I knew where I was.
这是我最后见到大猫咪附近的地方
I was near the last place I saw big kitten.
然后  我感觉到了
And suddenly, I felt it.
那条无形绳子  我又感受到了
The pull of that invisible leash, stronger than ever.
你知道我们要做什么吗  去宠物店
You know what we should do? Go to the pet store.
我们要买点狗粮
We need to get dog food.
达驰想让我留下来
Dutch wanted me to stay.
- 加入这个新家庭  - 狗狗们  别跑
- To be part of this new family. - Hey, hey! Hey, dogs! No, no, no.
别跑了  那边太远了
No, that's too far.
- 过来  - 来这边
- Come on!  - Come here.
- 分开理应很容易  - 听话 狗狗们  达驰
-It would have been so easy.  - Dogs! Hey, Dutch.
达驰  过来
Dutch.  Come on.
狗狗们  过来  贝拉
Hey, dogs.  Come. Bella.
达驰
Dutch.
Dutch!
- 贝拉  过来  - 真棒
- Bella, come on.  - There we go.
- 达驰最终回家了
- Dutch had finally gone home,
- 回到了他应该回的那个家  - 达驰真乖
- to a home he deserved. - All right. Good boy, Dutch.
过来  贝拉  来这边
Hey, come on, Bella. Come here.
- 贝拉  快过来  - 真乖  待着别动
- Bella, come on. - There you go. Stay. Stay.
贝拉
Bella!
- 等一下  贝拉  - 回来呀
- Wait, Bella. Bella!  - Come here. Come here.
贝拉
Bella.
贝拉  回来
Bella, come!
贝拉
Bella!
达驰找到了他的卢卡斯
Dutch had found his Lucas.
过来  贝拉
Come on. Come on, Bella. Bella.
现在我要去找我的卢卡斯了
Now, I needed to find mine.
贝拉
Bella!
我又饿了
I was hungry again.
我想大猫咪了
And I missed big kitten.
还有达驰
And Dutch.
我必须要到有人的地方  才有东西吃
I had to find people places, so I could eat,
即使找东西吃的地方不在我回家的路上
even though they were out of my way to do go home.
我找遍了整个镇子
I looked all over town,
但是所有能找到东西吃的地方都关门了
but all the good hunting places were closed.
等一下  那是
Wait, is that...
炸鸡
Chicken!
就是这了
And there it was.
他们好像在等我过来
Like they knew I was coming.
拦住那条狗
Stop the dog!
♪ 山川是高的  山谷是矮的
♪ The mountain is high, the valley is low
此处BGM  “Free Ride”
歌手  Riot Riot featuring Andrea Wasse
拦下那条狗
hey! Stop that dog!
♪ 而你不知道要走哪条路
♪ And you're confused on which way to go
♪ 所以我过来帮助你
♪ so I've come here to give you a hand
抓住他  我抓住了
get him! I got him! Hey!
♪ 然后带领你走进极乐之土
♪ And lead you into the promised land
♪ 跟上来  随风翱翔吧
♪ come on and take a free ride
地板上的食物都留是狗狗的
food on the floor is always for the dog!
鸡肉  鸡肉  鸡肉肉
Chicken, chicken, chicken!
真好吃呀
It was delicious.
大猫咪肯定喜欢
Big kitten would have loved it.
你有可能需要点这个
Hey, maybe you could use some of this, huh?
给你一点水
Little water there?
真乖
Attagirl.
真棒
Good, baby.
没事的
It's all right. Hey.
你真漂亮
Yeah, you're beautiful. Yeah.
这是啥
Hey, what's this here?
让我看看  狗牌
Yeah, let's see. Yeah, dog tag.
你叫贝拉
It's Bella.
是的  他们也给我做了个狗牌
Yeah, they gave me a dog tag, too.
他知道我叫什么了
He knew my name.
- 我以前见过他吗  - 即使没有那些狗牌
- Have I seen him before?  - Even without the tags,
他们也把我的身体数据记录在案
they got my biometric data on file.
过来
Come on.
好样的
Attagirl.
- 不  - 好样的
- No.  - Attagirl.
纸片上  无家可归的宠物需要钱买狗粮  好人一生平安
他叫阿克塞尔
His name was Axel,
他总是用绳子栓着我
and he always had me on a leash.
- 你好呀  乖孩子  - 嘿
- Aw! Hi, sweet girl.  - Hi.
你真乖
You are so sweet.
- 给你  - 再见
- Here you go.  - Bye.
谢谢
Thank you.
生意真好  贝拉
Good for business, Bella.
他身上有我熟悉的东西
Something about him was familiar.
阿克塞尔和迈克一样难过
Axel was sad the way Mack was sad.
和妈妈一样难过
The way mom was sad.
我想出去玩  就像之前和狗群一样
I wanted to go have fun like I did with the pack,
但是阿克塞尔不明白  狗狗是需要玩耍的
but Axel didn't understand that dogs need to play.
放松  乖狗狗
Shh. Easy, girl.
我们相互取暖
We kept each other warm.
乖狗狗
Good dog.
他让我不再饿肚子
He made sure I was never hungry.
真乖  贝拉
Good dog, Bella.
慢慢的  天气变暖了
Slowly, the air got warmer.
但是阿克塞尔越来越难过
But Axel got sadder and sadder.
我觉得阿克塞尔不会给我解开绳子了
I didn't think Axel would ever take me off the leash.
我不喜欢被拴着
I didn't like being chained.
那感觉很不好
It didn't feel right.
我不知道怎么帮助阿克塞尔  还能同时照顾自己
I didn't know how to help Axel and still take care of myself.
我要回家
I needed to do go home.
我爱你
I love you.
只有咱们俩
It's just me and you.
你是我唯一的朋友
You're the only friend I've got.
我爱你  贝拉
I love you, Bella.
我爱你
I love you.
只有咱们俩  贝拉
It's you and me, Bella.
你和我
You and me.
贝拉  我爱你
Bella, I love you.
我爱你  贝拉
I love you, Bella.
我爱你
I love you.
我躺在阿克塞尔身边直到他没了心跳
I laid with Axel while the heat slowly drained away from him,
直到世界上没有了阿克塞尔
until there was no more Axel
他再也不会难过了
and he was no longer sad.
我像乖狗狗一样坐好
I sat, being a good dog,
想着会有人来找我
thinking someone would come for me.
没人来
Nobody came.
做乖狗狗没有用
Being a good dog didn't work.
就好像全世界都忘了我
It was as if the whole world had forgotten me.
但是我不能放弃
But I couldn't give up.
我很渴
I was so thirsty.
我要喝水
I needed water.
贝拉  这很重要
Okay, Bella, this is very important.
准备好了吗  好啦
You ready? All right.
跑回家
Go home.
就是这样
That's it.
跑回去  贝拉
Go home, Bella.
回家
Go home.
快来  这里有一条超棒的小路
Come on, there's a cool path down here.
等我一下
Hey, wait! Wait for me!
- 快点  你每次都很慢  - 才不是
- Hurry up. You're always slow.  - No, I'm not.
快看  有条狗
Hey, look. A dog.
有人来了
People.
- 它怎么了  - 我不知道
- What's the matter with it?  - I don't know.
小心它有狂犬病
Careful it doesn't have rabies.
不会有狂犬病的  你个傻子
Doesn't have rabies, you moron.
他被绑住了  乖狗狗
It's stuck. Good dog.
真乖
Good dog.
它被绑在什么上面了
It's chained to something.
那是什么  那里有具尸体
What... what is it? There's a body over there.
不可能
No way.
- 狗狗被绑在他身上了  - 他死了吗
- The dog's chained to it.  - Is he dead?
我觉得他死了
I think so.
你要干什么
What are you gonna do?
乖狗狗
Good dog.
从来没觉得水会这么好喝
Water never tasted so good.
我现在知道了  我的旅途比我想象中的
I knew now that my journey was much longer
要长很多
than I'd ever imagined.
两个冬天过去了
Two winters.
还要多少个冬天呢
How many more winters would there be?
我还能活几个冬天呢
And how many more could I take?
到处都是他们的气味
Their smell was everywhere.
他们又要猎杀我
They were hunting me again.
我就知道他们会来
I knew they would come.
但我不会让他们认为我害怕了
But I wasn't gonna let them think I was afraid.
那是
Is that...
是大猫咪
It is big kitten.
她变成超级大猫了
And she's a big, big kitten now.
♪ 有时候在我们的生活中
♪ Sometimes in our lives
此处BGM  “Lean on Me”
歌手  Jillian Edwards
♪ 我们都有痛苦
♪ we all have pain
♪ 我们都有悲伤
♪ we all have sorrow
♪ 但如果我们足够聪明
♪ but if we are wise
♪ 我们就会知道
♪ we know that there's
♪ 总会有明天
♪ always tomorrow
♪ 依靠着我
♪ Lean on me
♪ 当你还不够强大
♪ when you're not strong
♪ 我会做你的朋友
♪ and I'll be your friend
♪ 我会帮你坚持下去
♪ I'll help you carry on.
又能在一起的感觉真好
It felt so good fo be together again.
我知道大猫咪也是这么想的
And I could tell big kitten felt the same.
♪ 让你有人依靠
♪ Somebody to lean on
♪ 有人依靠
♪ somebody to lean on.
我知道卢卡斯见到大猫咪也会很兴奋的
I knew Lucas would be excited to meet big kitten.
我们就能一起睡在床上了
And we would all sleep together in the bed.
卢卡斯一定会需要一个更大的床
Lucas was definitely gonna need a bigger bed.
这可是个新味道
Now, that's a new smell.
我不知道这些是什么东西  我也不想知道
I don't know what those are, and I don't want to know.
大猫咪
Big kitten!
就快到了
There it is.
我要回家  找到卢卡斯
Go home and Lucas.
大猫咪想让我跟她走
Big kitten wanted me to follow her,
可我想让她跟我走
and I wanted her to follow me.
我知道  大猫咪不会跟我回家的
I knew then that big kitten would not be coming home with me
不会睡在一张床上的
to sleep on the bed.
我会一直是你的猫咪妈妈的
I will always be your mother cat.
我爱大猫咪
I loved big kitten.
但我知道  我再也见不到她了
But I knew I would never see her again.
牌子上  丹佛市  城市界限  海拔1600米
哦  有只狗
Oh! A dog!
小狗狗  到这来  到这来  狗狗
Puppy, come here! Come here, puppy!
过来  过来  狗狗
Come here! Come here, puppy!
你还好吗  是的
You okay? Yeah.
停下来吧  求求你们
Just stop. Please.
发生什么事了
What's happening?
- 来吧  - 停下来
- Come on.   - Please stop.
- 到这来  - 到这来
- Here, boy.  - Come here.
到这来  到这来
Come here, girl. Come here.
过来  狗狗
Come here, baby.
好疼啊
It hurts so much.
但我要坚持继续走下去
I have to keep going.
街道和房屋开始看起来熟悉一些了
The streets and the houses started to look familiar.
我终于做到了卢卡斯说的
I finally did what Lucas told me.
我完成了回家游戏
I did go home.
卢卡斯  妈妈
Lucas! Mom!
是谁啊  卢卡斯
Who's there? Lucas!
哦  天呐
Oh, oh.
你不能进来  出来
Okay, you can't be in here. Come on.
所有的东西都不一样了
Everything was different.
出来  出来
Come on. Come on.
你出来的话  我就给你拿好吃的
I'll give you a treat if you come outside.
卢卡斯  妈妈
Lucas? Mom?
他们去哪了
Where were they?
这里有只流浪狗跑到我家里来了
There's a stray dog that just pushed its way into my house.
我能闻得出  他们已经离开了很久很久了
I could smell they had been gone for a long, long time.
我那么努力   我走了那么远
I tried so hard, and I'd come so far.
我实在是一步都走不动了
I just couldn't take another step.
猫咪妈妈
Mother cat?
你怎么变得这么小了
How did you get so small?
- 是你打电话说  这儿有只流浪狗的吗  - 是的
- Call about a stray dog?  - I did.
- 是你  - 是你
- You.  - You.
猫咪妈妈看着我离开  就像大猫咪之前一样
Mother cat watched me leave, just like big kitten did.
我猜  猫咪就是这么道别的
I guess that's how cats say goodbye.
只剩一个地方能试着找找卢卡斯了
There was just one more place to look for Lucas.
- 回头见  - 再见
- See you.  - Bye.
- 这里有狗  - 是的  是个乖狗狗
- Dogs?  - Yeah, that's a good boy.
之前就只有我一个的
I used to be the only one.
- 呃 奥莉薇亚   - 什么
- Um, Olivia?  - What?
我好像看见一条流浪狗跑过去了
I think a stray dog just came through.
♪ 我能感受到你的恐惧
♪ I'll feel the fear for you
此处BGM  “Don't Worry About Me”
歌手  Frances
♪ 我为你而哭泣
♪ I'll cry your tears for you.
闹铃响了  我就起来了
The alarm goes off, I get up.
♪ 就算我跌倒
♪ Even if I fall down
♪ 及时你不在身边
♪ when you're not around
♪ 不用担心我
♪ don't worry about me
不可能吧
No way.
♪ 我会爬上你面对的山峰
♪ I'll climb the hills you face
不可能
Can't be.
♪ 我为你做这些事
♪ I'll do this in your place
♪ 我会替你做任何事
♪ I'd do anything to go through it instead of you.
贝拉
Bella
是她  过来  过来  孩子
It is her! Come here! Come here, girl.
发生什么事了  孩子
What happened to you, girl?
什么  怎么了啊
What? What is it?
- 天呐  - 卢卡斯
- No. - Lucas?
这不可能
It can't be.
贝拉
Bella.
♪ 如果我跌倒  你也跌倒
♪ 'Cause if I fall, you'll fall
♪ 如果我站起来
♪ and if I rise
♪ 我们一起站起来
♪ we rise together
♪ 我笑的时候  你也笑
♪ when I smile, you'll smile.
卢卡斯  卢卡斯  卢卡斯
Lucas, Lucas, Lucas!
贝拉  贝拉  你还活着
Bella, Bella! You're alive.
我真是不敢相信
I can't believe it.
贝拉  这么久你都到哪里去了
Bella, where have you been all this time?
- 是贝拉吗  - 是的  真的是她
- Is that Bella?  - Yeah, it is. It really is.
贝拉
Bella.
我的天哪  都有两年半了
Oh, my god. It's been like two and a half years.
- 好久不见  - 卢卡斯  奥莉薇亚  妈妈
- Hi.  - Lucas! Olivia! Mom!
我真的回家了
I did go home!
她回来了  我知道  我知道
She came home. I know, I know.
你能打电话给兽医吗  告诉他我们在路上了
Can you call the vet, tell him we're on the way?
好的  好的  我去开车
Yeah. Yeah. I'll get the car.
卢卡斯  卢卡斯  门口有个执法人员说
Lucas? Lucas, there's an officer outside
你应该把狗交过去
who says you have to bring that dog out.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
开玩笑吧
You kidding?
没什么大事的
All right, everybody.
没什么大不了  没什么需要担心的
No big deal. Nothing to worry about.
我是为了那个斗牛犬来的
I'm just here for that pit bull.
如果你们任何人干涉的话
And if any of you interfere,
这些警官会逮捕你们
these officers, they will arrest you.
我们不想有任何麻烦
We don't want any trouble,
但我们必须要把狗带走
but we have to take that animal.
我想知道  为什么半个部门的人
I thought I'd see why half the department
都为了一个常规的动物管控电话跑出来了
is out here on a routine animal control call.
谁能跟我说说
Anybody want to fill me in?
队长  我到这来是因为正规公务  这些人
Captain, I'm here for a confiscation, and some of these people,
他们想把正常公务变成特殊状况
they're trying to turn it into some kind of a situation.
这是妨碍执法  收养危险动物
It's obstruction, harboring a dangerous animal,
违背合法的规定
and disobeying a lawful order.
你们谁能对这些行为负责啊
Well, which one of you is responsible for this crime spree?
我就猜到会这样
I thought it might be something like that.
是因为这个斗牛犬吗
That a pit bull?
我看着可不太像斗牛犬
Doesn't look like a pit bull to me.
她是我的狗  而且她受伤了
She's my dog, sir, and she's hurt.
我要带她去看兽医
I'm taking her to the vet.
很抱歉的告诉你  查克说的是对的
Well, I'm sorry to tell you that Chuck's right.
我们需要把你的狗送去收容所
We have to take your dog in to the shelter.
好吧
All right.
如果你要这么做  你需要过我这关
But to do so, you've got to go through
第一营  第三海军战队  美国海军陆战队
the 1st battalion, 3rd marine division, United States marine corps.
第一步兵部队  陆军
1st infantry, army.
82空降师  美国陆军
82nd airborne division, U.S. army.
第六舰队  美国海军
6th fleet, United States Navy.
101空降师  呼啸之鹰
101st airborne, screaming eagles.
第四步兵师  美国陆军
4th infantry division, United States army.
你真的希望事件升级吗
You really want this thing to escalate?
你呢
Do you?
女士  我的工作是执法
Ma'am, my job is to enforce the law,
法律规定我必须收押这条狗
and the law says I've got to impound this dog.
这意味着  如果有必要用泰瑟枪和胡椒喷雾
Now, if that means tasers and pepper spray,
那我会使用的
then that's what it means.
根据丹佛市市规第八条例
Under Denver city ordinance 8-...
等等
Wait.
他说  丹佛市
He said "Denver."
对了
That's right.
这里不是丹佛市
But this isn't Denver.
- 这里是联邦财产  - 这是什么
- This is federal property.  - It's what?
退伍军人医院是联邦政府财产
The va hospital is federal property.
严格上来说  这里不属于丹佛市
It isn't technically a part of the city of Denver.
所以  就是这样了  队长
So, that's it, captain.
我们不会起任何争执  因为你在这没有执法权
There doesn't have to be a fight, 'cause you don't have jurisdiction.
你们俩在哪里服的兵役
So, where did you two serve?
- 巴士拉（位于伊拉克）  - 喀布尔（阿富汗首都）
- Basra.  - Kabul.
（阿拉伯语）我很抱歉
Hué, tet offensive.
没事了  结束了  收工吧
All right. Show's over. Let's pack it up.
太好了
Yeah.
如果我看到这条狗离开应该在的范围  我会让你靠边停车的
If I see this dog leave the premises, I will pull your car over.
不  你不会的
No, you won't.
查克  我接到了很多对你的投诉
Chuck, I get more complaints about you
比其他所有人的加起来还多
than all the other acos combined.
把公车交上去  我要把你从外勤队里调出去
Turn that vehicle in. I'm pulling you out of the field.
没有人可以因为一条狗去让人靠边停车
And nobody is pulling anyone over for a dog.
听懂了吗
Got it?
很好
Good.
我的天哪  贝拉  我们好想你啊
Oh, my gosh, Bella, we missed you so much.
我不太明白刚刚发生了什么
I don't understand what just happened,
但我知道肯定是好事
but I'm pretty sure it was good.
哦  看我在箱子里发现了什么
Oh, look what I found in the chest.
我都忘了
I totally forgot.
到这来  还记得吗  贝拉
Come here. Remember this, Bella?
卢卡斯的毯子
My Lucas blanket!
- 我想试个东西  - 好
- I wanted to try something.  - Yeah.
这是她小时候最喜欢的东西
This was her favorite thing when she was little.
但在她经历了那么多之后  我不知道她是否还记得
But after all she's been through, I don't know if she'll remember.
贝拉  你想要
Bella, do you want...
- 一点点奶酪吗  - 一点点奶酪吗
- A tiny piece of cheese.  - A tiny piece of cheese?
她记得
She does remember.
她真是条棒极了的狗狗
She's an amazing dog.
她的确是
She really is.
我真的到家了
I was really home
和卢卡斯  还有奥莉薇亚一起
with Lucas, and Olivia, too.
我在我应该在的地方了
I was where I needed to be.
♪ 你能听到我在呼唤你的名字吗
♪ Can you hear me calling out your name?
此处BGM  "Everywhere"
歌手  Ida Redig
♪ 你知道我跌倒了  但我不知道如何开口
♪ You know that I'm falling and I don't know what to say
♪ 大声些说出来
♪ speak a little louder.
大猫咪也在她应该在的地方了
And big kitten was where she needed to be.
♪ 你知道  我很自豪  我不会说出这些话
♪ You know that I'm proud and I can't get the words out.
♪ 我想和你走遍天涯海角
♪ I want to be with you everywhere
♪ 我啊
♪ Oh, I
♪ 我想和你在一起
♪ I want to be with you
♪ 你能听到我在呼唤你的名字吗
♪ Can you hear me calling out your name?
终于明白
Finally understood
那条无形绳子  把我引向卢卡斯
that the invisible leash that led me to Lucas
那根绳子  就是爱
was made of love.
他就是我的那个人
He was my person.
我就是他的那条狗
And I was his dog.